A Guide to the Thomas Fitz-Hugh Papers
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Thomas Fitz-Hugh Papers 1881-1906
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
556-c
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred to the Manuscripts Department by Tom Clark, Gifts and Exchange, Alderman Library.
Biographical/Historical Information
Thomas Fitz-Hugh (1862-1957) was born in Goochland County, Virginia. He received an M.A. degree from the University of Virginia in 1883. He taught at Bingham's School (North Carolina), Central University (Richmond, Kentucky), Bellevue High School (Goochland County, Virginia), and the University of Texas before he assumed the chairmanship of the School of Latin at the University of Virginia in 1902. Until his resignation in 1929, Fitz-Hugh enjoyed a reputation as an outstanding teacher and prolific scholar.
Scope and Content Information
This addition to the Thomas Fitz-Hugh papers spans the years 1881-1906. Included in this collection of the University of Virginia classics scholar are notes, notebooks, and miscellaneous papers pertaining to academic endeavors. There are also personal papers, diplomas and awards, newspaper clippings, and photographs.
The material in this collection chiefly reflects Fitz-Hugh's career as a professor and scholar. These papers relate primarily to classroom examinations and Fitz-Hugh's research in the classics.
Arrangement
The papers have been filed in the following order: personal correspondence, notebooks, notes, examinations, diplomas, certificates, and awards, pamphlets and announcements, newspaper clippings, and an unidentified photograph. Wherever possible, these papers have been arranged chronologically within the topic.
Contents List
- Personal Correspondence 1984 February - 1898 August (Box 1)
- Logic Notebook 1881 (Box 1)
- Latin Notebook n.d. (Box 1)
- German and Latin Notebook n.d. (Box 1)
- Notes on Classics n.d. (Box 1)
- Notes on The Spirit of Classic Culturen.d. (Box 1)
- Notes and Photographs on Greece n.d. (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous Academic Notes 1889 November - 1892 May (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous Academic Notes 1894 March - 1900 (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous Academic Notes n.d. (Box 2)
- Latin Examinations 1894-1897 (Box 2)
- Diplomas, Certificates, and Awards 1892 February - 1904 December (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous Pamphlets and Announcements 1897 March - 1900 January and n.d. (Box 2)
- Newspaper Clippings 1898 and n.d. (Box 2)
- Photograph of an Unidentified Woman n.d. (Box 2)